Andrew Naylor Riefenstahl

Austin, TX 78704 (817)-897-4599

andrew.riefenstahl@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrewriefenstahl

Professional Summary

Compelling **educator** & **developer** who writes and instructs using high-fidelity online educational materials and coursework to drive student learning. Teaches computer science fundamentals, programming logic, HTML, CSS, and Javascript through engaging audio and video resources. Motivates self and team members using sincere, focused interpersonal communication. An experienced, results-oriented leader in person, online, and professional communities.

Education

2009-2013

Bachelor of Science, Anthropology

Texas State University, San Marcos, TX

Relevant Coursework: Osteology, Cognitive Behavior, Archaeology. Geology Minor: Chemistry, Mineralogy, Historical Geology, and Philosophy of Science.

2017-Present

Web Developer Certificate

Austin Community College, Austin, TX

Relevant Coursework: HTML5, CSS, Javascript, PHP, JQuery, Node.js, MongoDB, Adobe Creative Suite.

Experience

2019-March 2020

Web Development Curriculum Writer Hello World Studios, Austin, TX

- Writes interactive and engaging HTML/CSS/Javascript curriculum for the K-12 audience.
- Manages the regional team of web development curriculum writers/developers.
- Scripts and creates online learning resources through screencasting, audio engineering, and video editing.
- Teaches online, in the classroom, extracurricular settings, and after school programs.
- Oversees production, development, and quality control for online educational resources.
- Develops new curriculums for uncharted disciplines and emergent learning objectives. i.e. Sonic Pi, a Ruby programming playground taught in the form of music.

2018-2019

High School Computer Science Teacher

KIPP Brave High School, Austin, TX

- Develops curriculum, focused on the fundamentals of computer science, ranging from debugging skills, language acquisition, client ethics, and the role of technology in modern society.
- Internalizes Collegeboard AP Computer Science Standards, integrating them into meaningful lessons.
- Creating advocacy programs to build diversity in the computer science industry for future generations.
- Lead students in building unique algorithms that have real-world applications.
- Ensures class information and lesson materials are current with technological trends.

2017-2018

12th Grade Special Education Teacher

KIPP Austin Collegiate, Austin, TX

- Manages a caseload of students' Individual Education Plans (IEP) and 504 plans.
- Tracks and monitors student progress aligned with: IEP goals and objectives, academics behaviors, specific learning disabilities, transition plans, and behavior interventions.
- Communicates effectively with administrators, families, and staff to schedule ARD/504 meetings in advance of the due dates.
- Facilitates quality discussions regarding student progress using a holistic approach.
- Supports co-teachers by handling student modifications, grade tracking, and lesson planning for differentiated instruction.
- Provides tutoring in AP Language, AP Stats, & AP Environmental Science for students with grades that fall below passing during progress reports periods.
- Leads study skills course for students needing improved study habits and extra time.

2016-2017

Paraprofessional Special Education

KIPP Austin Leadership Elementary, Austin, TX

- Coaches students in responsive social-emotional cool down and control techniques.
- Supports teachers and administrations as integral floater teacher.
- Prepares leadership course and character development lessons.

2014-2016

Middle/High School/STEM Science Teacher East Austin College Prep, Austin, TX

- Engages 6-12th grade students by creating a safe learning environment to encourage the academic stretch.
- Prioritizes multiple work projects, from an administrative level to classroom subsystems.
- Implements creative lesson plans that are in alignment with TEKS and National College Board standards.
- Role-models for professional and ethical behavior to low income, at-risk youth.
- Sponsor middle school science fair team at Austin Regional Science Fair (2016).

Knowledge & Skills

Knowledge: HTML5, Advanced CSS3, Flexbox, Grid Layout, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, SASS, Javascript, Jquery, Node.js, NPM, MongoDB, Express, Babel, Webpack, ES6, C Language, Command-Line Manipulation, WordPress, Squarespace, Visual Code Studio, Sublime Text 3, Brackets, Windows OS, Mac OS, Microsoft Office, Google Drive, Office 360, Social Media, CATI Software, Adobe Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Media Encoder, Cubase 10, and more...

Certificates & Professional Development

- AP Environmental Science Curriculum and Instruction Certificate (2016)
- Special Education Certification (2017)
- Texas Teacher Certification (2016)
- TExES Science 4-8 & Pre-AP Science Certificates (2014)
- Middle School Science Mentor Teacher Recognized by National Board of Educators (2014)
- Professional Learning Committee (PLC) Professional Development (2015)
- Positive Behavior Intervention and Support (PBIS) Professional Development (2015)
- Pedagogy and Professional Responsibility Certification (2015)
- English Language Learner and Language Objectives Professional Development (2016)
- Texas Computer Education Association (TCEA) Professional Development (2016)